# **Amdjed Bensalah**

ML ENGINEER · DATA SCIENTIST

Paris. France

📕 +33744265064 | 💌 a.bensalah@esi-sba.dz | 🖸 github.com/amdjedbens | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/amdj3d | 🕻 amdj3dax

### **Personal Profile**

A final year student standing between AI, data and everything that has to improve codes and lives. With 1+ years of experience specializing in Machine Learning, Python development & Data Science. Primarily, looking for AI & MLOps engineering roles.

### **Education**

### **PARIS-SACLAY University**

Paris, France

MSc. In Virtual Reality and Intelligent Systems

Sept 23 - Current

- Deep learning for computer vision
- Pattern Recognition and Biometrics
- · Multi-source data processing

### Ecole Supérieure en Informatique 08 Mai 1945

Sidi Bel Abbes, Algeria

Sept 2018 - July 2023

MSc in Computer Systems Engineering

- · Analyze and design Deep Learning models.
- Define the needs and architecture of software.

# **Professional Experience**

IRT SystemX Palaiseau, France

Machine Learning Intern

March 2024 - August 2024

- Evaluated the effectiveness of AI models in terms of precision, security, and privacy protection.
- Adapted existing techniques of differential privacy to specific use case requirements.
- Contributed to the development of an API ensuring these functionalities.

**Epsidy** Nancy, France

Machine Learning Intern Feb 2023 - July 2023

- Worked on a project around realtime ECG signal analysis & segmentation that is used to help cardiologists in the diagnosis.
- Improved inference time of the deep learning optimized model from 4s to 3ms during my internship.
- Deploy AI models into realtime production in Nvidia Jetson Nano.

Realistic Security Algiers, Algeria

Systems Automation Trainee

Sept 2021 - Oct 2021

- · Development of an Ansible playbook to automate the installation and configuration of a penetration test environment.
- · Conducted thorough testing and bug fixes, ensuring software reliability.

# **Projects**

### Real-time ECG Signal detection using DL on edge devices

Academic & commercial project - with Epsidy

Feb 2023 - July 2023

- The realization of a real-time R-peak detection app using deep learning techniques on edge devices.
- I worked on the ML models optimization & deployment on edge devices part.

#### Get-10 (LLM)

Personal project Avr 2023

- Developed an app that leverages GPT-3 to answer school course questions based on teachers' lectures data.
- · Dockerized & Deployed on a web page to be used.

### Spam Detection System (NLP)

Academic project Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

- The realization of a Spam Detection System using state-of-the-art BERT model to be implemented in Google Add-on as interface for user.
- I worked on the ML part & reporting specifications and lead the team.

### **Edurika Bot**

Freelance Project Nov 2020

- · A chatbot that provided hundreds of students with information about the topics covered in previous exams.
- Built using the Telegram-bot API, and has been interfaced using python.

1

### Skills

**Machine Learning** Python, Pandas, Numpy, Sickit-learn, Pytorch, Tensorflow.

**DevOps** Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Docker, DigitalOcean, Ansible, Git.

Programming Languages Python, Java.

**Databases** MariaDB, MySQL.

**Hardware** Raspberry PI, Jetson Nano

**Other skills** Agile, Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging presentation.

## **Achievements**

#### **CSAW'22 FINALS**

7th place for "OctaCore" at CSAW'22 CTF Finals held at NYUAD, Abu Dhabi, UAE.

Nov 2022

#### AI HACK Tunisia 2.0

10th/300 place at the advanced NLP challenge, Tunisia

Aug 2022

### **Google Hash Code**

1st place for "OctaCore" at HASH CODE QUALS held at Alphabit Hub, ESI SBA, ALGERIA.

Feb 2022

### AlphaCTF 1.0

2nd place for "OctaC0re" at Capture The Flag competition, ESI SBA, ALGERIA.

Feb 2022

#### Hack.INI CTF 2021

3rd place for "OctaCOre" at Hack.INI the annual computer security event held at ESI ex INI, ALGIERS.

Nov 2021

### **Coding Challenge 3.0**

4th place at the Coding Challenge Competition (v3), ESI SBA, Algeria.

Jun 202

## Languages\_

English Professional proficiencyFrench Full professional proficiency

### Activities\_

- Contributing to open source projects that relates to cyber-security and machine learning.
- Since 2020, I have been an instructor at workshops on Machine Learning, Python Programming.